Matteo Graizzaro

Game Programmer

I decided to get into videogames when I first realized the amazing experiences I got to play in my early age, where developed by real people, and it helped that my skills in programming where needed, making it a viable career. This didn't stop me to try and become an "idea guy" for a while, but once I settled down in coding I felt at home.

While growing professionally I got to travel and connect with others, and that made me realize how vast, diverse, and dynamic the industry is. That's why I stuck around, and I can't wait to see more of it.

Contact

Linkedin

in/matteograizzaro

Email

graizzaromatteo@gmail.com

Website

vacui.github.io

Education

2020 | Padua, IT

Game Design

Event Horizon School

2017 | Valdagno, IT

Computer Science

I.T.I.S V.E Marzotto

Language

Italian

■ Native

English ● Proficient

Skills



TS Typescript



🕅 Nakama



Experience

Oct 2021 - Present Whatwapp



Read More

Mid Game Developer - Burraco Team

- Took responsibility for migrating existing game features from the old GameSparksbased server infrastructure to the new Nakama one
- Participated in the definition of company-wide standards to improve the back-end features scalability, and applied them to my area of competence
- Collaborated with the UI/UX Department to develop an on-boarding feature that lead to an improve in D3 Retention, D7 number of Matches finished, D7 hours spent in game and Adv. revenues, between +6 and +8%
- Reworked the tutorial of an existing feature, leading to an increase of 100% in the user's effectiveness in using the system
- Designed and implemented client and server-based multiplayer game systems
- Tested the game extensively to spot and sequentially fix bugs and other edge cases
- Proactively supported the Customer Care Department, by giving them new tools for in-depth access of players' data, enhancing their overall productivity

Feb 2021 - Oct 2021

Farewell North | Translator

FAREWELL **N**•RTH

Read More

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 Solitaire | Unity Project



Read More

May 2021 - Jul 2021 Ploppem 2 | Unity Project



Read More

Feb 2021 - May 2021 Tunnel I Unity Project



Read More

Publications

What steam will look like in 3 years

Read More

Jan 2021 | Gamasutra [Featured]

By analyzing data gathered using Steam's official API, I try to predict the prices, numbers, and genres of games that will be released between 2021-23.

Going deep in the Steam reviews

Read More

Jun 2020 | Gamasutra

What can be said about the first 3 years of a free Steam game called Robocraft, by analyzing its review numbers and score, gathered using Steam's official API.